

# Software Developer

### **Personal Info:**

- GitHub
- LinkedIn
- Iran-Tehran
- (98)919-5062977
- saba.marzoughi18@gmail.com

#### **About Me:**

I'm a software developer with 2 years of professional full-time experience in frontend development, alongside 3 years of part-time learning and practice in this field. During this professional journey, I have gained valuable experience developing diverse projects, improving my skills in JavaScript programming language and development tools. In the spare time, I concentrate on selfimprovement and develop personal projects. I'm excited for my next challenge where I can develop and work on mobile/web applications and be a part of a strong software engineering team.

## Skills:

- Programming Languages
  - JavaScript, TypeScript
- Front-end technologies
  - HTML5, CSS3, SASS
  - React
- Design
  - OOP, FP
- Cross Platform Apps:
  - React-Native (Android, iOS)
  - Electron (Windows, MacOS)
- State Managements
  - Redux, Context
- ALM
  - GitOps
  - Postman
  - Jira, Trello, Figma
  - Strapi (Content Manager)
- DB solutions
  - Realm
- API paradigms
  - REST, GraphQL

#### **Education:**

Sep 2017 - Des 2021

 Bachelor of Computer Engineering (Software)

# **Professional Experiences:**

## Front-end developer at UniPlato:

Australia (Remote),

Visit Project

Aug 2022 - May 2023

**UniPlato** is a team consist of more than 15 members developing "**Coffee**" platform which is a meeting platform for scheduling and managing meetings with individuals or group of people.

- Upgraded the "Coffee" platform by refactoring the old code structures of 2 old modules and bringing the modules back to the project.
- Enhanced platform stability by conducting more than 5 code reviews for new team members.
- Strengthened the codebase by developing over 15 pixel-perfect, responsive and well-structured **React** components, making the components accessible to all team members across all the modules as part of the project design system.
- Delivered over 10 new features, complete with demos, to the platform through collaborative communication with team members and the adept utilization of REST API and web sockets.
- Directed the Mac desktop app functionalities, prioritising features and managing development to align with user needs and business objectives.
- Collaborated with the new/junior team members to tackle challenges and overcome obstacles.

## Front-end developer at Comfortel:

Russia (Remote),

Visit Project

Dec 2021 - May 2022

**Comfortel** is an Internet service provider company that the team is consist of over 15 members developing "**Techpal**" project which consists of different platforms: Inkpal, Chatpal, Gitpal.

- Elevated team communication by implementing customizations across the Mattermost platform, ensuring a seamless experience on desktop (Windows and Mac) using **Electron** and mobile on Android operating system.
- Enhanced the usability of the "Techpal" platform by launching the
  desktop application on three different operating systems (Windows, mac,
  and Linux) with Electron, while also developing the Android application
  using React-Native.
- Documented the codes, ensuring that provides clear explanations for other developers to easily comprehend different sections of the codebase.

### Front-end developer (Freelancing):

Tehran,

Visit Project

Nov 2020 - Des 2021

**MyPlayer** is an open-source React Native project, serving as an audio/video provider platform. This platform utilizes Strapi as the content management system and also the app is accessible on both iOS and Android operating systems.

- Transitioned from class-base structures to functional ones, to harness the power of hooks. This transformation let to a remarkable 30% performance enhancement particularly noticeable on older Android devices.
- Refactored old code structure that resulted in removing 3 useless and extra packages from the project and reduced the bundle size.

## Front-end developer at Bytino:

Tehran

Nov 2019 – Nov 2020

**Bytino** is a startup team comprising frontend, backend, designer members with primary mission being the creation of outstanding webpage.

- Improved team's portfolio resulting in the acquisition of 2 new projects by creating one-page websites that showcased the team capability.
- Created 2 webpages templates that have the potential to expedite project implementation.